<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Intelligence from Yorke: relating the unlavvfull proceedings of the malignant party there: with some of their propositions</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 6KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 4 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A87289</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99859217</idno>
  <idno type="VID">111286</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2248509038</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing I263</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Thomason E114_12</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R12120</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99859217</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99859217e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A87289)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 111286)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Thomason Tracts ; 20:E114[12])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Intelligence from Yorke: relating the unlavvfull proceedings of the malignant party there: with some of their propositions</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>6, [2] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>August, 25. Printed for H. Blunden,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London] :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1642.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Place of publication from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="geographic_name">York (England) --  History, Military --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Great Britain --  History --  Civil War, 1642-1649 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-05 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-07 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-07 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:111286:1"/>
            <p>INTELLIGENCE <hi>FROM</hi> YORKE: RELATING THE VNLAWFVLL PROCEEDINGS OF The Malignant party there: WITH SOME OF THEIR PROPOSITIONS:</p>
            <p>
               <hi>August,</hi> 25. printed for <hi>H. Blunden.</hi> 1642.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:111286:2"/>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:111286:2"/>
            <head>INTELLIGENCE FROM YORKE.</head>
            <opener>
               <salute>SIR,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">O</seg>UR feares in the North increase as much as yours in the South, nay, more; you have a considerable strength, an Army of Horse, as well as of Foote to flie to for protection: We have neither; but on the contrary, those that oppose the Parliament, doe begin to pull of their vizard, which had all this while, written in its forehead; <hi>A Guard for his Majesties person:</hi> And doe begin to make that Guard an Army, now that his Majesty is removed, and that pretence taken a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>way, and whereas they pretended all this while to maintaine the <hi>Known Lawes of the Land,</hi> doe now exercise that for which there is <hi>no Law.</hi> As, to im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pose upon the Countrey, to raise the Summe of nine thousand pounds, or thereabouts: to compell them to maintaine a certaine number of Horse, and
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:111286:3"/> Foote at their owne charge, and such as shall re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuse, to be severely proceeded against before the Commissioners of Oyer and Terminer, which they have supplicated his Majesty to leave behinde him at <hi>Yorke:</hi> which will prove to this County as bad as the Star-Chamber, or High-Commission, and though divers of these persons, most forward in this action gave their Votes in Parliament to take away the Court at <hi>Yorke,</hi> under which they so long groaned, endeavour now to settle a Court by Commission of Oyer and Terminer, more Arbi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary then the former: Since these men doe intend by force to settle such a power as this, to over-awe this County; We expect that the Parliament, and Kingdome help us to breake the neck of this de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>signe in its infancy, it being intended to be put in execution throughout the Kingdome, and so the Malignant party shall have power by a Commis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sion of Oyer and Terminer, under the great Seale, to call before them all such persons as shall refuse to finde Horse Armes, or Money, to comply with their Propositions, they shall be disarmed, their monies taken from them, and the persons of the most considerable men to be secured: Witnesse the Commitment of Master <hi>Stapleton</hi> in Yorkshire, and Captaine <hi>Lister</hi> in Lincolnshire, and that this their project may not faile, the Forces of Horse and Foote they have prepared, shall compell obedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ence, and so all the true hearted Protestants shall be lest destitute of help, and imprisoned, as men
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:111286:3"/> disaffected to the King, because they are disaffected to their wayes.</p>
            <p>The like Commission and Force is setled in Lin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>colnshire, and those are to be in the Commission of Oyer and Terminer, that are Commissioners of Array: In Yorkshire they have added Sir <hi>William Belt,</hi> and Sir <hi>Tho: Harrison,</hi> two Lawyers, who affirme they know no Known Law that will war<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant such courses, which so much betrayes the Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berty and Property of the Subject, as these doe.</p>
            <p>The substance of the Propositions agreed unto by a packt Graund-Jury for the purpose, (witnesse Sir <hi>Robert Heath) Robin Hillyard</hi> (the grand Delin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quent to both Houses of Parliament) being fore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man of this Jury, were to this effect. <hi>viz.</hi>
               <list>
                  <item n="1">
                     <hi>1.</hi> THat on the <hi>24.</hi> of <hi>August,</hi> All those of this County that are charged with Horse, doe ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>peare at <hi>Yorke,</hi> and the Defaulters to be se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verely proceeded against by the Commis▪ of <hi>Oyer</hi> and <hi>Terminer.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item n="2">
                     <hi>2.</hi> That they shall maintaine their Horses for one Moneth, from that day.</item>
                  <item n="3">
                     <hi>3.</hi> That the Earle of <hi>Cumberland</hi> shall have under him Sir <hi>Thomas Glemon,</hi> and two Cavaliers more to mannage the affaires of War.</item>
                  <item n="4">
                     <hi>4.</hi> That a Commission of <hi>Oyer</hi> and <hi>Terminer</hi> bee settled at <hi>Yorke,</hi> directed to the Commissioners of <hi>Array,</hi> with two, or foure Lawyers more to be added</item>
                  <item n="5">
                     <pb n="6" facs="tcp:111286:4"/>
                     <hi>5.</hi> That the Earle of <hi>Cumberland</hi> remaine Gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rall here, and have a large Commission, and keep his Troope.</item>
                  <item n="6">
                     <hi>6.</hi> That his Majesty will send some field pieces.</item>
                  <item n="7">
                     <hi>7.</hi> That the King will freely give the Wardship of the Sons of those slaine in this War, on his Majesties Party.</item>
                  <item n="8">
                     <hi>8.</hi> That the Sheriffe be required to deliver the Countries Magazine to the Earle of <hi>Cumberland.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item n="9">
                     <hi>9.</hi> That his Majesty at setting up of his Standard at <hi>Nottingham,</hi> will dispense with the attendance of the Gentry of <hi>Yorke,</hi> that have listed themselves to serve under his Majesty.</item>
               </list>
            </p>
            <p>THese were in substance delivered in the name of divers of the Inhabitants of this Country, (though by thousands disclaimed) who pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pounded 8672. li. to be a Summe fit to be present<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly raised, with this Preamble; That the King was driven from his Parliament: That many Members of both Houses, persons of reall Fortune, have withdrawne themselves from the Parliament, pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>titioned for redresse, and one of their Messengers imprisoned, and therefore doe now seek to his Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jesty for protection.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:111286:4"/>
            <p>
               <hi>To these nine Propositions his Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jesty condescended, saving the leaving of piece of Ordnance at</hi> Yorke, <hi>of which he would consider, and conclu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deth, that since the Gentlemen of</hi> Yorkshire <hi>are resolved not to desert his Majesty, hee will either protect them, or perish with them.</hi>
            </p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>